LISA VINSON | software developer

experience

Software Engineer I | Renaissance Learning

November 2023 - Present, Remote

- Develop and enhance user interfaces for school management applications used by teachers, administrators, parents, and students using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Vue.js.
- Partner with developers across teams to expand API functionality to allow integration between suite of educational applications using JWT
- Troubleshoot SQL stored procedures and VB.NET bugs in educational software to ensure accurate grade book calculations and state reporting.

Technical Support Manager | White Whale Web Services

December 2021 - November 2022, Remote

- Resolved level 2 and 3 support requests for college admins and developers to comply with Federal accessibility laws and resolve core software bugs.
- Designed and developed billable client customization projects to improve process automation, mobile responsiveness, and extend software features:
 - O Purchase College: Automated process for admins to highlight events as meeting campus sustainability goals (PHP, SQL, JavaScript, jQuery)
 - Southwestern University: Extended CMS functionality to allow campus editors to create multi-day itineraries, replacing third-party software costing up to \$2000 per event (HTML, SASS, JavaScript, PHP, SQL)

Junior Web Developer | White Whale Web Services

November 2020 - December 2021, Remote

- Developed university calendar management websites, ensuring mobile responsiveness and WCAG accessibility compliance.
- Managed new client launch processes in AWS, including installing SSL certificates (Certificate Manager, EC2), creating DNS entries (Route53), and enabling Apache server virtual hosts.

Teaching Assistant & Grader | UCF Coding Bootcamp

August 2018 – December 2020, Orlando, FL / Remote

- Introduced software development concepts to students, focusing on HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Node, Express, MySQL, and MongoDB.
- Hosted office hours to provide one-on-one tutoring and group focus sessions on agile methodology, JavaScript, and application deployment.

Software Developer I | CentralSquare Technologies

April 2019 - March 2020, Lake Mary, FL

- Resolved production bugs in complex finance and HR management applications used by governments using VB.Net, C#, Genero, and SQL.
- Solo developer on a cross-application feature to allow expansion of payroll deduction types and employee choices of deduction options.

contact

- Atlanta, GA
- **4**07-808-8607
- www.lisavinson.com
- in lisavinson1
- LiVinson

profile

Software developer with a focus on continuously improving ability to write clean, testable, and maintainable code, regardless of tech stack.
Leverages experience in devops, technical support, and QA testing to understand users, their needs, and how to provide simple solutions to complex problems.

skills & knowledge

HTML

CSS (SASS/LESS)

JavaScript

jQuery

TypeScript

React

Redux

Vue.js

Express

Node.js VB.NET

PHP

SQL & Sequelize

MongoDB & Mongoose

Firebase

AWS

Jest & Enzyme

Webpack

LISA VINSON | software developer

experience

QA Analyst I | CentralSquare Technologies

May 2018 - March 2019, Lake Mary, FL

- Authored and executed Azure DevOps test cases each sprint.
- Performed cross-browser and operating system testing with BrowserStack

Client Delivery Manager | PeopleScout

April 2017-August 2017, Charlotte, NC

- Led requirements meetings with clients to determine business needs, define scope, and document new processes.
- Performed root cause analysis of client issues, providing recommendations that reduced average client escalations by 80% in 3 months.

Sr. Operations Specialist | PeopleScout

February 2014 – April 2017, Charlotte, NC

- Designed training curriculum for core processes, facilitating in-person and virtual training sessions for up to 30 employees in four geographic locations.
- Conducted monthly quality assessments of clients' hiring process to ensure compliance with company guidelines and federal law.

applications

Taboo! Multiplayer Team Game | https://playtaboo.app

React, Redux, React Router, Styled Components, Firebase, Node.js, Jest, Enzyme

- A mobile-first online version of the popular board game that pits friends against each other to describe a particular word without saying anything from the "taboo" list. Play when physically together or while socially distanced via online meeting platforms.
- Displays varying views based on each player's team and current role in the game with real-time updates of actions performed by other players.
- Designed using Figma and deployed to Firebase using Jenkins for continuous integration and deployment.
- Administrative program to review card ideas submitted by players, review system errors, and import data from CSV to create or update game cards.

Hacker News Clone | https://hacker-news-react-clone.netlify.app

JavaScript, React, React Router, Context API, Webpack, Babel

- Fetches data from the Hacker News API and displays the top and new story headlines
- View story details, comments, and user profiles. Toggle between a light or dark theme.
- Bundled and compiled with custom Webpack and Babel configuration and deployed using Netlify.

contact

- Atlanta, GA
- **4**07-808-8607
- www.lisavinson.com
- in lisavinson1
- LiVinson

education

University of Central Florida

April 2018

Full Stack Web
Development, Certification

Tarleton State University

December 2015

HR Management, MS

University of Florida

May 2012

Sociology, BA

interests

drawing

boxing

basketball

hiking

kayaking